## Clayton Salinger Ketner

www.claytonketner.com ⊠ claytonketner@me.com ☎ (650) 533 9695

Home: 1407 Tarrytown st.

San Mateo, CA 94402

School: 817 W. 30th st.

Los Angeles, CA 90007

## ${f INTRODUCTION}$

Fifth year (of five) undergraduate Mechanical Engineering and Computer Science student with strong practical experience, close attention to detail, and an interest in robotics, design, and fabrication. Friendly and effective team leader able to quickly adapt to changing environments and technologies.

	EDUCATION
	Major: Mechanical Engineering – Minor: Computer Science
Fall 2011 – Spring 2014	University of Southern California   GPA: [fall '13]: 3.71 – Graduate B.S. in May, 2014
	$\label{eq:capprox} A dvanced\ computer\ aided\ design\ (CAD\ +\ FEA),\ linear\ control\ systems,\ dynamic\ systems,\ vibrations,\ heat\ transfer,\ advanced\ strength\ of\ materials,\ engineering\ algorithms,\ robotics\ algorithms,\ artificial\ intelligence$
Fall 2009 – Spring 2011	University of Massachusetts, Amherst   GPA: [major]: 3.58 - Transfer to USC
	Statics, dynamics, strength of materials, thermodynamics
	EXPERIENCE
Fall 2013 (4 Months)	Design of a Mechanical Governor – AME 408 Final Project – Managed team to design a rotating governor part, given deformation and natural frequency requirements using SolidWorks. Tags: LEADERSHIP   TEAMWORK   SOLIDWORKS   CAD   FEA – <u>more info</u>
Fall 2013 (4 Months)	Intro to Robotics – CSCI 445 – Learned localization (particle & Kalman filters), mapping (SLAM & FastSLAM), decision processes (MDP & POMDP), and sensor calibration and use.  Tags: ROBOTICS   ARDUINO   RASPBERRY PI   ALGORITHMS   SENSORS – <u>more info</u>
Fall 2012 (4 Months)	Senior Project — Remote Inspection Vehicle — Remote control robot for the 2013 ASME design competition. Designed and built the controller. Coded and wired the controller and robot.  Tags: CAD   DESIGN   LEADERSHIP   CODE   WIRELESS   ROBOTICS — <u>more info</u>
Summer 2012 (2 Months)	Robotic Arm – Designed, manufactured, wired, and coded independently and from scratch.  Tags: CAD   CNC   DESIGN   FABRICATION   CODE   MATLAB   ROBOTICS – <u>more info</u>
Summer 2011 (3 Months)	<ul> <li>OSIsoft - Virtual Campus Intern (40 hr/wk)</li> <li>Independently researched and integrated OSIsoft PI System with SAS analytics.</li> <li>Gave two live progress presentations to the Virtual Campus team.</li> <li>Concluded findings in a White Paper posted to OSIsoft's vCampus website.</li> </ul>

## $\mathbf{SKILLS}$

 $\bullet$  = 1 year of proficient use SOLIDWORKS & SIM ●●● SOLID EDGE € PRO-E **●** TECHNICAL REPORTS ●●● Engineering LABVIEW • CONTROL SYSTEMS ●● MATLAB & SIMULINK ●●● MATHEMATICA ● HAND TOOLS ●●●● MECHATRONICS ●● ROBOTICS ●●**( ELECTRONICS PROTO ●●** Hands-On 3D PRINTING ( CNC MILL/ROUTER **€** MACHINE SHOP ●● JAVA & JUNIT ••• PYTHON ● ( C++ ● LATEX ●◀ Programming UI & UX ● WEB DEVELOPMENT ( Miscellaneous WORD & EXCEL ●●●● COMMUNICATION •••• LEADERSHIP ●●

• Received praise from an outside company for quality of the White Paper.

2011 – Present **Sigma Phi Delta** – Professional Engineering Fraternity – Active member – (Fall 2013) House Manager & Executive Board Member

2014 – Present  $\ \mathbf{USC}\ \mathbf{Aerial}\ \mathbf{Robotics}\ \mathbf{Team}\$  – Mechanical team

Fall 2013 Dean's List (USC) Spring 2010 Dean's List (UMass)

March 2012 Certified SolidWorks Associate - Score: 100%